<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mechanics on Mobile Robot I/O</title>
    <link>http://mobilerobot.io/categories/mechanics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Mechanics on Mobile Robot I/O</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://mobilerobot.io/categories/mechanics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>On Vehicle Communication</title>
      <link>http://mobilerobot.io/projects/on-vehicle-communications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mobilerobot.io/projects/on-vehicle-communications/</guid>
      <description>One of the first issues that we came against was the specific configurations of the micro-controllers as well and the number and configuration of pins and hardware particulars.
Macro-Micro Controllers The system should be flexible enough to allow one or more macro-controls communicating with one or more micro-controllers.
Communication Mechanism We have a rather complex set of communication requirements, we have signals between sensors, motors and micro-controllers. We also have the communication from the micro-controllers and the macro-controller.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chasis and Drive Train</title>
      <link>http://mobilerobot.io/projects/chassis-drive-train/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mobilerobot.io/projects/chassis-drive-train/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A system as complex as a self driving vehicle is the combination of the
integration of a few complex projects.  This page will keep us updated
on the current projects and status of these projects.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chassis and Drive Train</title>
      <link>http://mobilerobot.io/notes/reqs-hw-chasis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mobilerobot.io/notes/reqs-hw-chasis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The body and drive train of the Robot will determine if our project is
going to actually function in the real world.  It all starts with a
design in mind, choices of materials, the design of all functional
components, mobility, motion and durability of the project.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>