<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Field Notes Robot Building on Mobile Robot I/O</title>
    <link>http://mobilerobot.io/notes/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Field Notes Robot Building on Mobile Robot I/O</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://mobilerobot.io/notes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The Mobile Robot Project</title>
      <link>http://mobilerobot.io/notes/project/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mobilerobot.io/notes/project/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We want to build a self&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Robot must be able to navigate while controlled by a human or
software, it must be modular, extensible and configurable.  Interested
in the project?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Source Robotics Projects</title>
      <link>http://mobilerobot.io/notes/related-projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mobilerobot.io/notes/related-projects/</guid>
      <description>I did not realize it at the time I started the MobileRobot.IO project that what I was setting out to build is what is commonly reffered to as a Rover. Basically a wandering vehicle typically to do some form of discovery.
Rovers Here is a two wheeled Rover that connects an (Arduino and a Raspberry Pi over an I2C bus)[https://www.hackster.io/peejster/rover-c42139].</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenCV Installing and Getting Started on Raspberry Pi</title>
      <link>http://mobilerobot.io/notes/opencv-getting-started/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mobilerobot.io/notes/opencv-getting-started/</guid>
      <description>Install OpenCV on a raspberry pie, at least how I have been trying to do it, by downloading the source code and building has been a very tedious task, for which I have yet to celebrate any form of success.
On to Plan B Therefore I think I am going to head off and try plan B, for now Plan B is one of the following three options:
 Use PXE to boot The raspberry pie and mount the file systems over NFS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Arduino Pro Mini</title>
      <link>http://mobilerobot.io/notes/arduino-pro-mini/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mobilerobot.io/notes/arduino-pro-mini/</guid>
      <description>I bought this thing for $7.99, it does not have a usb connected nor the requesit circuitry to upload programs with,
The Pro comes without the mini-USB connector and hence requires a FTDI serial adapter to load the software on the chip.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Micro Controller Communication Options</title>
      <link>http://mobilerobot.io/notes/micro-communication-options/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mobilerobot.io/notes/micro-communication-options/</guid>
      <description>Our vehical is required to support at least power 4-DC motors, 2 Servos for the camera&amp;rsquo;s Pan &amp;amp; Tilt functions. There will be at least one camera, perhaps more streaming video. There will be an assortment of sensors, including distance, atmosphere, LED lights and so on.
Lot&amp;rsquo;s of stuff going on That being the case, we will keep a couple Arduino&amp;rsquo;s and a Raspberry Pi busy keeping our Robot vehicle rolling.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Draw I/O and SVG Images</title>
      <link>http://mobilerobot.io/notes/draw-io-and-svg-images/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mobilerobot.io/notes/draw-io-and-svg-images/</guid>
      <description>I have created my first (but not last diagram with Draw.IO). I guess the important part is incorporating the SVG graphics. They are so clean and scalable, however they can also be automated and linked from.
This is just the begining.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Programming the NRF240L1 RF Tranceiver</title>
      <link>http://mobilerobot.io/notes/programming-the-nlrf24l01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mobilerobot.io/notes/programming-the-nlrf24l01/</guid>
      <description>This RC reciever chip is very easy to use out of the box, yet provides some very sophisticated capabilities. The first project We&amp;rsquo;ll start using this chip will be a remote control Joystick for our mobile robot.
Todos:  point to the datasheet load personal photos of my project with NRF20L  pull the image from evernote  fritz a diagram post code that I use and or wrote Try to do an eagle cad  Source Voltage According to Benjamin David Fraser Plugging the NRF24L02 directly into the Arduino 3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Arduino Interupts</title>
      <link>http://mobilerobot.io/notes/arduino-interupts/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mobilerobot.io/notes/arduino-interupts/</guid>
      <description>Nick Gammon does a great job describing interupts on the Arduino, when and I why you might want to use them. As an overly summarized version, if you want to be able to get a notification when data has arrived without having to sleep and poll for data.
Talk about Ardiuno interupts, non-blocking I/O and Nearly Real Time OS. This is a very good, and very indepth article.
TODO: Add some code snippets as examples for running external engines.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Arduino Nano</title>
      <link>http://mobilerobot.io/notes/arduino-nano/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mobilerobot.io/notes/arduino-nano/</guid>
      <description>I flashed the onbaord LED and I made the RGB LED change colors. It is powered with a old style mini (small) USB adaptor.
I was able to connect the Arduino Nanos to the I2C bus created for internal communications.
Power can be brought in through a 5v Vin pin.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Connecting a Raspberry PI and Arduino with I2C</title>
      <link>http://mobilerobot.io/notes/i2c-rpi-arduino/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mobilerobot.io/notes/i2c-rpi-arduino/</guid>
      <description>When I first started tinkering with the Arduino, about mid 2018, (yea I know, I am waaaaay late to the game) It was so easy to find great tutorials, but that changed quickly once you start filling up the pins you need.
 The Whole is Greater than the sum of the parts
 References:  [Nick Gannon ~ Excellent and thourough](&amp;ldquo;http://www.gammon.com.au/i2c&amp;quot;) &amp;ldquo;http://dsscircuits.com/articles/effects-of-varying-i2c-pull-up-resistors&amp;quot; &amp;ldquo;https://oscarliang.com/raspberry-pi-arduino-connected-i2c/&amp;quot;  Macro and Micro Controllers One attractive thought is using the Raspberry PI and it&amp;rsquo;s full blown OS, programming and communication capabilities as the brains and transport.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tank and The Internets</title>
      <link>http://mobilerobot.io/notes/reboot/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mobilerobot.io/notes/reboot/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As Tank roams about, it will be gathering and transmitting data
according to the application, that data will be collected, by a
collector and sent to storage.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OSEPP Tank Kit</title>
      <link>http://mobilerobot.io/notes/osepp-tank-kit/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mobilerobot.io/notes/osepp-tank-kit/</guid>
      <description>TODO: Place some photos, and pointers to everything.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Large Scale Video Delivery</title>
      <link>http://mobilerobot.io/notes/mcast-video-delivery/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mobilerobot.io/notes/mcast-video-delivery/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I lead a team at Cisco Systems to build a system that would deliver
streaming video to millions of users, simultaneously. That same
technology has been used by DIRECTV, TimeWarner Cable, AT&amp;amp;T and
other major&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TFTP Display with Adafruit 2.8 LCD</title>
      <link>http://mobilerobot.io/notes/rpi-adafruit-tftp-display/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mobilerobot.io/notes/rpi-adafruit-tftp-display/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The number #1 thing to make sure of is select the first option in the ADA TFT
function.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reconfigure the Raspberry Pi by Rebooting</title>
      <link>http://mobilerobot.io/notes/raspberry-pi-network-booting/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mobilerobot.io/notes/raspberry-pi-network-booting/</guid>
      <description>Booting a Raspberry Pi from an SD card or USB stick is pretty neat and all, but they are inadequate for sustainded, reliable production use.
The quality of the SD comes into question immediately. Even the best of SD cards can go south out of nowhere! I do not know much about sd cards at all, except that I have blasted through about 12 of them this with 3 RPI&amp;rsquo;s (and a BeableBone), that is too expensive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Management This Website</title>
      <link>http://mobilerobot.io/notes/websites/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mobilerobot.io/notes/websites/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Even what at first glance would seem to be the simplist of websites
will end up being a lot of work, if that site is to become
productive.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sensor Networks</title>
      <link>http://mobilerobot.io/notes/sensor-networks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mobilerobot.io/notes/sensor-networks/</guid>
      <description> TODO: write ups  sierra hydrographics ACOE GOES software timeseries databases example sensor network around the house (throw in hardware)  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Go Schedular in Depth</title>
      <link>http://mobilerobot.io/notes/go-scheduler-in-depth/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mobilerobot.io/notes/go-scheduler-in-depth/</guid>
      <description>This is a three part series:
 part2: https://www.ardanlabs.com/blog/2018/08/scheduling-in-go-part2.html  PS Look at the company for inspiration</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DC Power, Batteries and Solar</title>
      <link>http://mobilerobot.io/notes/power/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mobilerobot.io/notes/power/</guid>
      <description>Different options for powering robots. Stationary, near electrical outlets is always the easiest, but does not bode well for mobile and autonomous.
Batteries are the key factor.
Make a list of my various power supplies.
Also make a link to the Youtube video that shows how to make a multi voltage power supply from an old PC power supply.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Software Development</title>
      <link>http://mobilerobot.io/notes/software/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mobilerobot.io/notes/software/</guid>
      <description>This document will attempt to capture and define some Software best practices that we&amp;rsquo;ll practice during our software development process.
Zero Downtime Software Also, how can we manage the software on a live robot? This sounds like a job for industrial strength, distributed system with a friendly API. Is it possible?
Oh, it has to be all OpenSource. It is entirely acceptable, and preferable to use other well established Open Source products.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Requirements ~ The Controller</title>
      <link>http://mobilerobot.io/notes/reqs-controller/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mobilerobot.io/notes/reqs-controller/</guid>
      <description>The controller has two primary parts, the hardware and sofware elements. A good system design, like ours will separate the specific hardware and the controlling software.
Hardware Requirements  wireless ~ but which  The vehicle will be automous, hence it needs to be free of tethers, both electronics, controls and power.
 must be responsive, there should be no (minimized) percievable delay from  TODO: Determine HW Control type There are a number of choices to select for HW control, RFI seems to be a good candidate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Robotics and IoT</title>
      <link>http://mobilerobot.io/notes/robotics/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mobilerobot.io/notes/robotics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The world is full of things that rely on software to work, from
sprinkler systems, to cars and jet airplanes, laptops, cell phones and
drones.  You name it everything. Now lets consider how we use it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Arduino vs Raspberry Pi</title>
      <link>http://mobilerobot.io/notes/rpi-vs-arduino/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mobilerobot.io/notes/rpi-vs-arduino/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My goal is to build a very simple RTOS communication module for the
on-board vehicle control system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;limitations-of-hardware&#34;&gt;Limitations of Hardware&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Arduino is the workhorse of the maker world, for very good reason,
but I quickly realized I was running out of pins for all the things I
wanted to attach to Arduino.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A motorshield on one Arduino, and a large number of sensors will
overwhelm the hardware power of one of these devices.  More important,
the processing power can easily become overwhelmed with some of the
smarts required for the driving algorightms and moving time-series
data into the clowd.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For that reason we will setup a Micro/Macro Controller arrangement for
our purpose.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Arduino is perhaps the greatest things to ever happen for the
Weekend Warrior wanting to play &lt;em&gt;Electrical Engineer&lt;/em&gt; (which is me).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Arduino comes with a mind numbing option of extreemly cheep (or
expensive and sophisticated) after market eco system of input sensors,
motors and so on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Arduino, is THANKFULLY very simple to use. This also means that it
lacks a lot in comparison with the full blown operating system.
&lt;em&gt;Mobile Robots&lt;/em&gt; requires a rather complex combination of inputs
sensors (distance, temprature, atmosphere), cameras (live video) and
outputs such as electric motors, leds, speakers and displays.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chassis and Drive Train</title>
      <link>http://mobilerobot.io/notes/reqs-hw-chasis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mobilerobot.io/notes/reqs-hw-chasis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The body and drive train of the Robot will determine if our project is
going to actually function in the real world.  It all starts with a
design in mind, choices of materials, the design of all functional
components, mobility, motion and durability of the project.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Messaging and MQTT</title>
      <link>http://mobilerobot.io/notes/messaging-and-mqtt/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mobilerobot.io/notes/messaging-and-mqtt/</guid>
      <description>TODO: I need to get enough architecture together to build out my Robot Control time system</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>