<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Software on Mobile Robot I/O</title>
    <link>http://mobilerobot.io/categories/software/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Software on Mobile Robot I/O</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://mobilerobot.io/categories/software/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Skid Steering</title>
      <link>http://mobilerobot.io/notes/skid-steering/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mobilerobot.io/notes/skid-steering/</guid>
      <description>Skid steering basics
 Based on fixed direction wheels[1] or tracks There are two groups or sides of wheels: left and right All wheels in a group MUST always point in the same direction All wheels in a group MUST always rotate at the same rate Direction is determined by the speed of the two wheel groups  To move straight all motors rotate at the same rate Forward and Reverse are determined by positive and negative values Turning is achieved by varying the throttle on the right and left   Example The Skidder class has the following API, as you can see all of the movements we desire can be accomplished with a single API call</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Raspberry Pi Motor Control Software</title>
      <link>http://mobilerobot.io/projects/rpi-motor-control-service/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mobilerobot.io/projects/rpi-motor-control-service/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TODO ~ replace image with one of the Raspberry Pi Controller&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This software adds a Skid Steer motor control software to the
&lt;a href=&#34;http://github.com/mobilerobot-io/rpid&#34;&gt;Raspberry Pi Device Server&lt;/a&gt;
device server.  RPID adds motor controls accessible via both MQTT and
REST APIs, as well as directly with the Skidder python library.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Control Station Display</title>
      <link>http://mobilerobot.io/notes/touch-screen-display/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mobilerobot.io/notes/touch-screen-display/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We are going to build a simple control station that begins with a
Raspberry Pi and connected &lt;em&gt;7 inch touchscreen tablet&lt;/em&gt;.  I have it
setup in &amp;ldquo;kiosk mode&amp;rdquo;, which is basically full page chrome without the
tabs and tool bars etc.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TLV the Type Length Vector Protocol</title>
      <link>http://mobilerobot.io/projects/tlv-and-realitime-communication/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mobilerobot.io/projects/tlv-and-realitime-communication/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;TLV is a very simple communication protocol that can be used to send
messages around a complex, distributed system.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Raspberry Pi Flask and MQTT Master Control Server</title>
      <link>http://mobilerobot.io/projects/rpi-flask-mqtt-server/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mobilerobot.io/projects/rpi-flask-mqtt-server/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This application provides access and control to various Raspberry
devices like the camera, GPIO pins, or a possible MotorShield if
needed.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Raspbery Pi Camera Control Service</title>
      <link>http://mobilerobot.io/projects/rpi-camera-control-service/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mobilerobot.io/projects/rpi-camera-control-service/</guid>
      <description>I have created a python / Flask based server to run on the Raspberry accepting REST calls to perform application specific functions.
I have created a flask server that will accept REST requests to control the PiCamera, AdaFruitMotorSheild and other stuff.
Refer to the PiCamera documentation here: https://picamera.readthedocs.io/en/release-1.13/.
The software can be found in github repository.
And how to write and operate a flask based server for your project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Otto the Pluggable Macro Controller Micro Service</title>
      <link>http://mobilerobot.io/projects/otto-master-controller-micro-service/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mobilerobot.io/projects/otto-master-controller-micro-service/</guid>
      <description>Otto is a small, simple micro-server written in Go. It handles requisit communications and related infra structure required by servers and controllers. The applications and functionality will be provided via pluggins.
Otto can run as a REST server in a data center or the controller on micro-controller type of computer. Otto was developed with the notion that much of the code that makes for a good server (or any application for that matter) requires redundant but import supporting infrastructure.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>