<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Robotics on Mobile Robot I/O</title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/categories/robotics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Robotics on Mobile Robot I/O</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="//localhost:1313/categories/robotics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Chassis and Drive Train</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/notes/reqs-hw-chasis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//localhost:1313/notes/reqs-hw-chasis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The body and drive train of the Robot will determine if our project is
going to actually function in the real world.  It all starts with a
design in mind, choices of materials, the design of all functional
components, mobility, motion and durability of the project.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Requirements ~ The Controller</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/notes/reqs-controller/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//localhost:1313/notes/reqs-controller/</guid>
      <description>The controller has two primary parts, the hardware and sofware elements. A good system design, like ours will separate the specific hardware and the controlling software.
Hardware Requirements  wireless ~ but which  The vehicle will be automous, hence it needs to be free of tethers, both electronics, controls and power.
 must be responsive, there should be no (minimized) percievable delay from  TODO: Determine HW Control type There are a number of choices to select for HW control, RFI seems to be a good candidate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mobile Robot I/O Project</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//localhost:1313/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Building a useful Robot is hard, in large part because Robotics is an
inter-disciplinary subject matter requiring a high level of mastery of
a number of complex subjects, (some of which we have listed below).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mobile Robot I/O Projects</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//localhost:1313/projects/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Mobile Robot I/O Project is more than a single project, really it
is a group of projects related to building, running and maintaining a
mobile robot.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>