<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Active Projects on Mobile Robot I/O</title>
    <link>http://mobilerobot.io/projects/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Active Projects on Mobile Robot I/O</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://mobilerobot.io/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Control Systems</title>
      <link>http://mobilerobot.io/projects/control-system/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mobilerobot.io/projects/control-system/</guid>
      <description>This project, the control system will determine how easy or difficult it will be to integrate various controls both human and automated.
Problem Definition The robot must be controllable by a variety of methods that include both human and computer controls. To accomplish this goal, it is essential that the software is developed as modular and inter-conencted.
Requirements Our drive system must be able to adapt to various steering algorithms including skid, Ackerman and Rear Assisted stearing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Vehicle Communication</title>
      <link>http://mobilerobot.io/projects/on-vehicle-communications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mobilerobot.io/projects/on-vehicle-communications/</guid>
      <description>One of the first issues that we came against was the specific configurations of the micro-controllers as well and the number and configuration of pins and hardware particulars.
Macro-Micro Controllers The system should be flexible enough to allow one or more macro-controls communicating with one or more micro-controllers.
Communication Mechanism We have a rather complex set of communication requirements, we have signals between sensors, motors and micro-controllers. We also have the communication from the micro-controllers and the macro-controller.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zumo Bot Control Mods</title>
      <link>http://mobilerobot.io/projects/zumo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mobilerobot.io/projects/zumo/</guid>
      <description>TODO: talk about the changes to the Zumo bot and what they accomplished.
 Project Description
 Circuits used
 Software used
 Mechanical Parts used
 Videos and images of project
  On so forth.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>